Guide to the Verdi Burtch papers, [ca.1894]-1943.
Burtch, Verdi papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Verdi Burtch papers, [ca.1894]-1943.
3288
Burtch, Verdi,
1.8 cubic ft.
Photographs, Research Materials, Scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Scrapbooks, photographs, and volumes of bird observation notes. Also, 18 notebooks of Verdi Burtch's and Clarence Stone's bird observations and a catalog of bird and plant photographs arranged by species.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Verdi Burtch was an ornithologist in Penn Yan, Yates County, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Scrapbooks, photographs, and volumes of bird observation notes. Also, 18 notebooks of Verdi Burtch's and Clarence Stone's bird observations and a catalog of bird and plant photographs arranged by species.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Burtch, Verdi, 1868-1945.; Stone, Clarence.
Subjects:
Ornithology.; Ornithologists.
Places:
Penn Yan (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Notebooks.; Scrapbooks.; Photographs.; Field notes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- "Unpublished" Bird Manuscripts, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Manuscripts by Burtch, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Some Warblers I have Found" (with photographs), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "The Piping Plover, Common Tern and Black Tern Colonies of Sandy Pond and Point", undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Reprints by Verdi Burtch, 1914-1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Banding Schedule, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Notes and Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographs (some by C.F. Stone), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Verdi Burtch Memorial Lecture poster, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, 1896-1935 (Box 1, Volume 1)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, 1931-1945 (Box 1, Volume 2)
- Photograph Album (Birds and Nests), c. 1910-1915 (Box 1, Volume 3)
- 3 panorama photographs of American Ornithologist Union Meetings, 1929,1928,1929 (Folder 1)
- Catalog of Photographs - birds and plants by species, c. 1913-1938 (Box 2)
- Bird Notes (Verdi Burtch), 1885-1899 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Bird Notes (Clarence F. Stone), 1889-1904 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bird Notes, 1893-1896 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Photocopy of Bird Notes 1893-1896 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Bird Notes, 1894-1901 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Photocopy of Bird Notes 1894-1901 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Bird Notes, 1896-1898 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Photocopy of Bird Notes 1896-1898 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Bird Notes, 1896-1903 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Photocopy of Bird Notes 1896-1903 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Bird Observation Logs, 1896-1920 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Bird Notes, 1899-1920 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Bird Notes, 1904-1907 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Bird Notes (Clarence F. Stone), 1905-1913 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Bird Notes (Clarence F. Stone), 1913-1922 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Contains musical notations of bird song
- Bird Notes, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Field Journals and Bird Notes, 1922-1924 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Catalog of Skins, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Bird Notes, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Bird Notes and Bird Journals, 1929-1933 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Bird Observations, 1936, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Travel Log and Photocopy of Travel Log (undated), undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Bird Poetry and Bird Observations by Andrew Flag Robson, 1925-1928 (Box 3, Folder 23)